Paulina Jonéus

Curriculum vitae

CONTACT INFORMATION

Paulina Jonéus

Phone: (+46) 730 299 118

E-mail: paulina.joneus@gmail.com

OBJECTIVE

My main research interests are in statistics and causal inference, focusing on statistical methods in health economics and medical research. In addition, I am particularly interested in study designs, observational studies, time series modelling, and machine learning methods.

EDUCATION

2017 - Ph. D. student, Uppsala University, Department of Statistics

Dissertation topic: Methods in Causal Inferences.

Advisors: Mattias Nordin (main) and Per Johansson.

On parental leave for a total of 10 months in 2021-2022.

2015 M. Sc., Statistics, Uppsala University

2013 B. Sc., Statistics, Uppsala University

2013 B. Sc., Economics, Uppsala University

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

2016–2017 Desk officer at the Ministry of Finance, Stockholm 2015-2016 Statistician at Statistics Sweden, Stockholm

PUBLICATIONS

- 2021 Study protocol for a comparative effectiveness evaluation of abiraterone acetate against enzalutamide: a longitudinal study based on Swedish administrative registers, *BMJ Open, BMJ*, doi.org/10.1136/bmjopen-2021-052610 (with Johansson P., and Langenskiöld S.)
- A Study Protocol for an Instrumental Variables Analysis of the Comparative Effectiveness of two Prostate Cancer Drugs, arXiv:2110.04164 (with Johansson P., and Langenskiöld S.)
- A study protocol for a comparative effectiveness evaluation of antiandrogenic medications against Standard of Care, arXiv:2110.02698 (with Johansson P., and Langenskiöld S.)
- 2021 Simulation smoothing for nowcasting with large mixed-frequency VARs, *Econometrics* and *Statistics*, doi.org/10.1016/j.ecosta.2020.05.007 (with Ankargren S.)
- 2019 Estimating Large Mixed-Frequency Bayesian VAR Models, arXiv:1912.02231 (with Ankargren S.)

Paulina Jonéus 2

MANUSCRIPTS IN SUBMISSION

The deregulation of the Queensland electricity market and a smooth transition duration model, diva2:1552475 (with Lyhagen, J.)

MANUSCRIPTS IN PREPARATION

Causal Inferences and Real-World Evidence: A comparative effectiveness evaluation of abiraterone acetate against enzalutamide (with Johansson P., and Langenskiöld S.)

Docetaxel versus New Hormonal treatment – a registry based comparative effectiveness evaluation for mCRPC-patients (with Johansson P., and Langenskiöld S.)

Machine Learning Methods and EHR Data – A matching strategy

PROJECTS

2018– Part of a methodological project funded by The Swedish Dental and Pharmaceutical Benefits Agency (TLV). The objective is to serve as a template of how to use the Swedish administrative population registries and quality registers in conducting comparative effectiveness evaluations of interventions

PRESENTATIONS AND OTHER ACTIVITIES

Presentations and department talks

- 2022 Dept. of Statistics (UU)
- 2021 Dept. of Statistics (UU)
- 2019 CMStatistics (London, UK); Dept. of Statistics (UU); UppUpp (UU and SLU)
- 2018 Dept. of Statistics (UU)

Participation

- 2019 Three-day course with Professor Guido W. Imbens: Methods in causal inferences for health economics and medical research, HEFUU, Uppsala
- 2017 CMStatistics (London, UK)
- 2017 Women in Statistics and Data Science (San Diego, USA)

DEPARTMENTAL SERVICE

Member of the committee of equality, Department of Statistics, 2018-2021 Board member, Department of Statistics (student representative), 2014-2015

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

2021	Academic Teacher Training Course, Uppsala University
2017–2022	Ph. D. student with teaching duties (20 %), Uppsala University, Department of
2013–2015	Statistics and Department of Informatics and Media Teaching assistant, Uppsala University, Department of Statistics

Paulina Jonéus 3

Course director and instructor

Introductory Statistics (2022)

Instructor and teaching assistant

Probability theory (2018-2021)

Introductory Statistics (2018)

Time Series Econometrics (2018)

Time Series Analysis (2017-2018)

Econometrics (2017-2018)

Applied statistical methods (2017-2018)

Supervisor

1 bachelor thesis (2019)

COMPUTER SKILLS

Programming

R, Python, SAS, Stata, MATLAB, LATEX

LANGUAGES

Swedish (native)

English (fluent)

REFERENCES

References available upon request